# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

Address: P.O. Box 668-40100, Kisumu

Cell-phone: +254-722-424-639

E-mail: adudap2018@gmail.com

Profession: Child Protection and Community Development Specialist

Nationality: Kenyan Passport No: A069350 Relevant experience: 15 years

### **SUMMARY OF CAPABILITY**

Over 15 years' experience working with civil society, communities, the public and private Sectors on issues of community empowerment, governance, citizen participation, accountability, community organizing, social research, policy formulation and implementation. Have been actively involved in building the capacity of citizens and organizing them to actively participate in different livelihood options that enhances community wellbeing and dignified living. My work has been with communities in both rural and urban in various programmes tailored to protect and promote human rights as well as rally efforts geared towards ensuring that policy declarations are matched with practical steps to address issues that concern the marginalized and vulnerable members of the community. Have worked with different organizations and donors (such as the Bernard Van Leer Foundation(BvLF) and Netherlands Embassy, Swedish Cooperative Centre, Sida, EU, DfID and OSIEA and as well worked with agricultural, fishing and pastoral communities and counties across Kenya in institutionalizing Social Accountability in Devolved Governance. I have acquired relevant post graduate trainings & experience key among which include a Master Trainer on mainstreaming Psychosocial support and care, community conversations, Governance, as well as community organizing; mainly involved in Community Entry Processes, training and Facilitation, stakeholder engagement and citizen participation.

Board of Management (BOM) Member-Kanyamedha Secondary School (Kisumu) March 2022 to date

Board of Management (BOM) Member-Miyare ECDE (West Ugenya)-April 2022 to date

### **KEY CONSULTANCY WORK**

Co- Consultant/Trainer Dec 2023 **Pastoralist Community Initiative and Development** 

**Assistance (PACIDA)-Marsabit** 

Capacity strengthening for 20 CSOs in Leadership, governance and strategic management, Program Development, Project planning and monitoring

Co-Consultant/Trainer June 2023 County Government of Kisumu

Ethics and Integrity Training for Kisumu County

Inspectorate & enforcement staff.

Lead Consultant/Trainer	April 2023	Community Initiative Action Group Youth economic empowerment and involvement in governance in Siaya County
Team Consultant	August 2022	Community Initiative Action Group (CIAG) Corporate transformation focusing on conflict and diversity management, transformational and strategic management, good governance, integrity and ethics, Board Management and CEO relationship
Co-Consultant (Technical Expert) Kilifi County	July-Aug 2019	Catholic Relief Services(CRS) Final Evaluation for Child Protection mechanisms in the Coastal Kenya(Dialogue and Action Project Phase III
Lead Consultant: (Siaya County)	May-Sept 2018	Community Initiative Action Group (CIAG) (Tracking Health and Agriculture budget allocation and utilization in Siaya County for the period (2013-2017)
Lead Consultant: (Siaya County)	August 2018	Community Initiative Action Group (CIAG) Psychosocial Care and Support Training for ECDE teachers
Team Consultant (Turkana County)	June2017 to Jan 2018:	County Government of Turkana & Mercy Corps (Formulation of Community Policing Policy)
Lead Consultant (Siaya County)	October 2012	Plan International in Kenya Youth livelihoods and Agri-business uptake
Team member	June2005 Feb2006:	Women Action Forum for Networking Looking at the Nyanza Communities' beliefs and practices with gender equality and human rights lenses

### **WORK HISTORY**

Jan 2020 –Dec 2022 Grassroots Trust for Community Organization in Kenya

Position Policy & Community Organization Advisor

Supporting the community organizations and their networks to build formidable issue based units that identify and challenge structural deficiencies and power imbalances that sustain poverty and inequalities and proactively address complex community issues, influence good governance and redistribution of valued resources.

April 2015 to April 2017 **Independent Medico Legal Unit (IMLU)** 

Position **Programmes Manager-Kenya** 

Provided thematic support, technical assistance and programmatic guidance to Independent Medico-Legal Unit (IMLU) Governance, Health and Human rights programmes in Kenya. Assured the quality of Protection against Torture, Violence and Discrimination Programmes throughout the whole programming cycle (planning, implementation and evaluation/reporting). Was responsible for building and strengthening the knowledge, competence and capacity of relevant functions of staff and partners on community participation, advocacy and protection. Spearheaded the development of M&E framework for health, governance& human rights, protection & promotion programmes.

### **Summary of key roles**

- Coordinating efforts for access to justice for victims of torture, extra judicial executions and other forms of human rights violations through medical, legal and psychosocial support and ensuring effective case management system for the torture victims.
- Initiating and spearheading relationship building and stakeholder enhancement for greater programmatic impact and effectiveness with both National & County government officials as well as non-state actors
- Maintaining and ensuring rapport building with a network of professionals; lawyers.
   Journalists, human rights monitors and doctors through regular communication & interaction towards safeguarding the rights of all against torture, violence and discrimination.

Feb 2011 -October 2014 ChildFund-Kenya

### Position Area Programmes Manager-Nyanza & Western Region

Provided leadership to a multi-year Integrated Early Childhood Care & Development, Community-Integrated Management of Childhood Illnesses, Youth livelihood and health & Capacity building Programme, helping the deprived, excluded and vulnerable children access quality education, health and decent livelihood as well as overcome barriers such as child marriage, early pregnancies, stigma and discrimination and other forms of violations that limit their chances to experience their full potential and well-being.

### **Summary of key roles**

- Spearheaded efforts towards child protection systems & governance strengthening e.g. supporting Area Advisory Councils
- Ensuring effective case management system for child abuse cases & coordinating efforts for access to justice for child rights violations through medical & psycho-social support
- Advocating for effective and meaningful child participation in programmes
- Conducting trainings on legal and policy frameworks
- Supporting the formation of community based child protection mechanisms
- Ensuring sponsorship & program activities responded to OVCs & community needs

Feb 2008-May 2011: ChildFund-Kenya

### Position Project Co-ordinator (ECDE) -Siaya, Kisumu & HomaBay Counties

Spearheaded overall coordination and management of Integrated Early Childhood Care and Development Project, targeting the under-five cohort with a range of preventive, promotional and responsive services geared towards improving their well-being. This project was delivered in partnership with community and support from Bernard Van Leer Foundation (BvLF)-Netherlands

#### Summary of key roles

- Spearheading efforts towards child protection systems strengthening & governance e.g. supporting Area Advisory Councils
- Advocating for effective and meaningful child participation through child right clubs, assemblies, family set-ups and other related protective spaces.

### May 2007-Feb 2008: ChildFund Kenya

Position Field Officer (ECDE) Project –Nyakach Sub-County

# **Summary of key roles**

- Initiating and/or strengthening networks towards enhancing child protection environment
- Project planning, implementation, documentation and reporting

### Feb 2006- April 2007: Care Kenya

Position Field Officer Economic Empowerment (Voluntary Saving & Loaning) & HIV/AIDS Stigma Reduction Project (Kungo kod Hola)—Alego Usonga Sub-County

### **Summary of key roles**

- Mobilizing community members to form saving groups
- Project planning, implementation, documentation and reporting
- Planning and facilitating trainings on VSL, business selection planning & management (SPM)as well HIV stigma reduction strategies

# May2005 – Jan2006 Women Action Forum for Networking,

WAFNET/SIDA

Position Project Assistant (Research and Documentation)
Project Gender, culture and HIV/AIDS Project cum

Research Study

### **Summary of key Roles**

• Coordination of data collection and analysis in a research involving three communities in Nyanza on their cultural beliefs, traditional practices and myths within the context of HIV&AIDS, gender, illiteracy and poverty in relation to children and women rights

#### Accomplishment:

Played a key role in the analysis of the socio-economic and cultural data which culminated in the publication of widely acclaimed document with a framework of human rights perspective

entitled ''Looking at the Nyanza Communities' beliefs and practices with gender equality and human rights lenses'

**Nov 2001- Dec 2004** Citizen Coalition for Constitutional Change (4Cs)

Position Program Facilitator (Nairobi West District)

Project Advocacy and networking

# **Summary of key roles**

• Facilitated Civic Education forums focusing on thematic areas of governance and state, democracy, nationhood and Constitutional awareness.

#### **EDUCATION**

August 2016 MA Degree (**Social Policy**)

Maseno University (Research work underway)

2008-2009 Diploma in Project Management

Kenya Institute of Management

1994 – 1999 BA Degree (**Sociology & History**)

Egerton University – Kenya

1989 – 1992 Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (**KCSE**)

Maranda High School, Kenya

#### OTHER TRAININGS UNDERTAKEN:

### **February 2016** Leadership and Integrity training-by Poverty Eradication

Network

**Acquired**: Conceptual understanding of key leadership theories, leadership styles and behaviors, the three P's of leadership, leadership and management, conflict and diversity management, transformational & strategic management, good governance, integrity and ethics, Board, management and CEO relationship.

# October, 2009: Monitoring and Evaluation Mentorship Training

### **Areas covered:**

Conceptual understanding of M&E, Monitoring and evaluation as an integral component of project planning and implementation process, M&E Framework and Approach, M&E Data Collection and Analysis, Result based reporting

### **OTHER QUALIFICATIONS**

#### Seminars and Conference Attended- South Africa

• 6<sup>th</sup> Annual BvLF Partners Conference on Young Children and HIV&AIDS Durban, South Africa, Nov 17-21, 2013. Focused on strengthening the care and support

environment of young children against the backdrop of triple crises (**HIV&AIDS**, **Poverty and conflicts**. led a discussion team that reviewed the role of indigenous knowledge systems (**IKS**) in strengthening care and support for the young children within family and community set-up.

#### REFEREES

1. Mr. Aluso Aggrey

Pandemic Action Network

Director, African Region

P.O. Box 147-00100, Nairobi-Kenya

Tel: + 254 716 741 501 / +254 732 035 701

Email:aggrealuso@yahoo.com / aggrey.aluso@pandemicactionnetwork.org

2. Dr Sammuel Okuro (PhD)

AFRISOL CONSULTANT

Director

P.O Box 9043-40141 Kisumu-Kenya

Tel: +254 720 709 600

Email:afrisolkenya@gmail.com

3. Mr. Michael Ochieng

**B&M** Consultants

Team Leader

P. O. Box 38033-00632

Tel: +254 722-341998/+254 735 529 397

Email: mochieng@bmconsultke.com/ochiengjakisumo@gmail.com